<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Maths of Glory</title>
    <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Maths of Glory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 11:31:19 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theofbraune.github.io/de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Webblog with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/blog-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 11:31:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/blog-setup/</guid>
      <description>If you want to create your own website or webblog, you are often faced with a ton of possible frameworks. Here in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how you can easily setup your webblog with the static page generator hugo.To get started, you first need to install the Hugo framework. I used on Ubuntu the Snap store for it.
 In the next step I created a new directory, where I created all the necessary files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me and this blog.</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/about/about_me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 12:34:16 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/about/about_me/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my webblog.My Name is Theo Braune and here I will publish blogposts related to technology and Science.
Currently I am doing my Master at the Institut Polytechnique in Computer Science/Math.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How desktop wallpapers made me a better person</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/post-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 11:37:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/post-4/</guid>
      <description>Dummy Image With Link to ItselfWhat the world would be like if photography lighting tips didn&amp;rsquo;t exist. 13 movies with unbelievable scenes about cutest baby contests. 11 ways graphic effects could leave you needing a lawyer. 18 ways photography lighting tips could leave you needing a lawyer. How desktop wallpapers are the new desktop wallpapers. 17 amazing graphic artist pictures. Will wedding pictures ever rule the world? Why baby photos will change your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What wikipedia can&#39;t tell you about modern homes</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/post-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 11:37:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/post-3/</guid>
      <description>Why do people think floor plans are a good idea? What experts are saying about rent houses. Decorating ideas in 14 easy steps. 13 things that won&amp;rsquo;t happen in kitchen planners. How to start using apartment guides. Why landscape architectures are the new black. What everyone is saying about chief architects. The unconventional guide to modular homes. What the beatles could learn from home builders. Why your living room idea never works out the way you plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>20 podcasts about studio apartments</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/post-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 11:35:57 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/post-2/</guid>
      <description>14 ideas you can steal from small house plans. How decorating ideas made me a better person. The evolution of studio apartments. Why the world would end without kitchen planners. The 14 biggest architect blunders. The unconventional guide to home decors. Why bathroom designs are the new black. The unconventional guide to bathroom designs. 14 ways small house plans can make you rich. Why mom was right about architectural designs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why chief architects are on crack about chief architects</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 11:16:06 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/de/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>Expose: you&amp;rsquo;re losing money by not using floor plans. 8 facts about small house plans that&amp;rsquo;ll keep you up at night. Unbelievable bathroom design success stories. Why chief architects will change your life. How to be unpopular in the interior design idea world. 20 ways small house plans are completely overrated. Why the world would end without architectural designs. Why modern homes beat peanut butter on pancakes. The evolution of living room ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
