<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Theo Braune</title>
    <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Theo Braune</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 16:03:37 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conformal Parametrization</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/conformal_parametrization/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 16:03:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/conformal_parametrization/</guid>
      <description>In this TP we want to calculate the harmonic and the conformal parametrization of a mesh.
You will need to complete the class methods in the class ConformalParametrization that you will find in the file conformal.cpp. In order to see the goal of the TP, you can press 4 to use the pre-build Libigl method of the conformal parametrization on the mesh. A detailed description about the task and further information can be found in the original publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart Rate Measurement through Computer Vision</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/heart_rate_measurement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 13:15:57 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/heart_rate_measurement/</guid>
      <description>For many applications in telemedicine or in a security context a contactless heart rate measurement can be great interest useful. Most of the conventional approaches use a wearable object like a chest belt or a special watch. In the mentioned cases, this is not always applicable. Therefore one is interested in methods, that can extract the heart rate from a video feed.
This project was part of the Computer Vision introduction course at École Polytechnique and is mainly based on this article</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make it Stand - Balancing Shapes for 3D-printing</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/3d-printing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 18:00:10 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/3d-printing/</guid>
      <description>Through the evolution of 3D-printers, the it has become more and more easy to produce prototypes of 3 dimensional shapes. In this project we developed our first software to produce shapes and printable objects for a 3D-printer. This project was part as a final project of the École Polytechnique course &amp;ldquo;X-INF 573 Digital Representations and Analysis of Shapes&amp;rdquo;.
The aim of this project was to give an input shape, define an angle an orientation axis and then to carve out and deform the shape, such that the new modified shape can stand in this desired position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on the locomotion technique</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/reflection_locomotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 11:18:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/reflection_locomotion/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will summarize the work on the virtual reality project and reflect a bit what I experienced in the implementation process. First of all I should point out that unity is an extremely powerful platform and is easy to use, when having some programming experience. All these things like collision, drag and mass otherwise would be difficult to implement.
In the implementation process I was often improvising a bit to overcome difficulties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of the Ski-locomotion</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/evaluation_locomotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:27:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/evaluation_locomotion/</guid>
      <description>In order to evaluate the locomotion technique, I conducted a series of tests with our course participants that were familiar with the usage of virtual reality techniques and other people, that have not used VR technology in any form before. I discovered a discrepancy in the ease of use for these two groups. The group non familiar with this technology needed more attempts to get familiar with the haptic and the general environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity setup</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/unity_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:04:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/unity_setup/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will describe how I installed and set up the Unity Hub and editor on my machine.
First I went to the official unity page. This article assumes, that you have not installed unity yet. Thus you need to download the unity hub.
In this article I am using Windows, but the steps for the other operating systems are not that different. Of course you need to accept the unity licence agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roll a ball - Tutorial for a first game in Unity</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/roll_a_ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:03:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/roll_a_ball/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this article is to guide you through the process of creating your first game in unity. In order to do this start by your Unity Hub, click on new project and select for this tutorial 3D-Core. Give the project your favorite name and location. Now you should see the unity editor. In order to get started, select Assets/Create/Scene. In the assets tab of the editor you should now see an icon new scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of Ski Locomotion in Virtual Reality.</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/implementation_locom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 14:29:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/implementation_locom/</guid>
      <description>In my locomotion project I went for an approach to imitate cross-country-skiing in VR. The overall idea will be, that you have to move your arms from top to down, and this then gives you a push. I used the environment build by Wen-Jie Tseng, that he provided for our class under this link. This was my starting point, to modify the position of the OVRCamera Rig with its controllers, in order to move.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sutherlands vision of the Ultimate display and the Reality-Virtuality Continuum</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/ultimate_display/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 18:14:13 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/ultimate_display/</guid>
      <description>Who knows whether we are not all the time already in some kind of ultimate display&amp;hellip;.
In 1994 Paul Milgram published with a work, where he introduced the idea of a Reality-Virtuality Continuum. You can think of it in the following way: With the rise of technology, like smartphones or in general some Silicon Valley Hardware device, the line between what is reality and what is virtual becomes more and more unclear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up a Webblog with Hugo</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/blog-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 11:31:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/blog-setup/</guid>
      <description>If you want to create your own website or webblog, you are often faced with a ton of possible frameworks. Here in this post, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how you can easily setup your webblog with the static page generator hugo.
To get started, you first need to install the Hugo framework. I used on Ubuntu the Snap store for it.
In the next step I created a new directory, where I created all the necessary files.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
