<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Maths of Glory</title>
    <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Maths of Glory</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 11:18:11 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reflection on the locomotion technique</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/reflection_locomotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 11:18:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/reflection_locomotion/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will summarize the work on the virtual reality project and reflect a bit what I experienced in the implementation process. First of all I should point out that unity is an extremely powerful platform and is easy to use, when having some programming experience. All these things like collision, drag and mass otherwise would be difficult to implement.
In the implementation process I was often improvising a bit to overcome difficulties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity setup</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/unity_setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:04:26 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/unity_setup/</guid>
      <description>In this post I will describe how I installed and set up the Unity Hub and editor on my machine.
First I went to the official unity page. This article assumes, that you have not installed unity yet. Thus you need to download the unity hub.
 In this article I am using Windows, but the steps for the other operating systems are not that different. Of course you need to accept the unity licence agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Roll a ball - Tutorial for a first game in Unity</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/roll_a_ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 18:03:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/roll_a_ball/</guid>
      <description>The aim of this article is to guide you through the process of creating your first game in unity. In order to do this start by your Unity Hub, click on new project and select for this tutorial 3D-Core. Give the project your favorite name and location.  Now you should see the unity editor. In order to get started, select Assets/Create/Scene.  In the assets tab of the editor you should now see an icon new scene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementation of Ski Locomotion in Virtual Reality.</title>
      <link>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/implementation_locom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Jan 2022 14:29:19 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theofbraune.github.io/blog/posts/implementation_locom/</guid>
      <description>In my locomotion project I went for an approach to imitate cross-country-skiing in VR. The overall idea will be, that you have to move your arms from top to down, and this then gives you a push.
         Image Credits - https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WaMTbWNVRko    In the first part of my implementation, when playing with the given locomotion technique, I realized, that I can enter the ground.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
